foreign
using the Tosca API scan and Tosca
Commander now this is a series of videos
on API testing and this is the fourth
part in this particular Series so if you
have not watched the previous uh Parts
on this particular series then I would
recommend you to go back and watch all
the three videos prior to this so that
you can follow along what I'm talking on
this particular video okay
so we have already seen uh we have been
using this
um pet API to add some pets and then get
the new pet which we have added using
the ID and then
um to delete that a new pet from the API
right so these are the three requests
which we have scanned and then when we
have uh imported it to our project under
this particular component folder called
API testing and then all the modules and
test cases were already generated by
Tosca and then in the last session we
also saw uh how we can change or add
different business parameters like
module attributes and then we can also
do some verifications like the status
code and also the name which we have
added in the request right and that same
name we are verifying in the response so
these two verifications uh we have seen
how we can do this by adding business
parameters and then in the test case we
can do the verification right
now the next step is to uh basically
execute the get request and the delete
request but the only problem right now
is we need a pet ID in order to process
this request because it requires this
parameter which we need to pass which is
the pet ID
and this pet ID is generated only after
we send the post request right where we
are adding a new pet so once it is added
and then in the response we are getting
back the ID so we need to capture that
particular ID which is being returned by
uh the response
and then we need to pass that as a
parameter into our get request and
delete request right so that's what we
want to do
so if I look at the post at pet response
okay and here in the technical view you
can see that there is a ID okay this is
what it is returning so once we send the
post request this will be returned in
the response and this is what we want to
capture and we want to buffer it so that
it will be stored in some variable and
then we can use it as a parameter in all
the other requests where it is required
okay
so uh the first thing which we need to
do is uh we need to add this as a
business parameter so I'm going to
select this and I'm going to click on
ADD so now it is the ID is a module
attribute here which is like a business
parameter so it will be available
um in our test case as well right
also in the request right for this
delete and get request we also need to
add the pet ID okay because also the
delete request requires a API key so
both of these parameters should be added
okay so I'm going to add this here
and then in the get request I'm going to
add the pet ID
so these are the three module attributes
a one for get request two for delete
which we require okay
and then let's come back here and
so here we have got the ID so in the
response and what we want to do is we
want to basically store it somewhere so
that we can access it later on right and
the best way is to use the buffer right
so buffer uh we can use in the action
mode so we are going to buffer the value
which is returned from the ID okay
so I'm going to give it the action mode
buffer and then here I'm going to give
it uh basically
a buffer name right where this
particular ID will be stored okay
so
um let me call it pet ID
okay and maybe I can rename this as B
underscore pet ID
so this is my buffer on value or the
buffer name where this value will be
stored
um and once this is done then we can
come here uh in the delete request the
API key basically will remain same right
so it is not changing you can even
convert this into a configuration
parameter if you don't want to write it
directly here right
and then a pet ID here we are going to
use the buffer value okay so here B and
then B underscore pet ID
okay so this will be our buffered value
which we'll be using and same for the
get request again I will be using the
buffer value okay so we um we underscore
pet ID
thank you
okay so this is how you can basically
pass different values okay which you are
getting from a response uh you can
basically filter out those values and
you can store it somewhere like a
buffered a buffer value right and then
use those values in other request
wherever uh you are requiring those
those values right so it is basically a
chaining of requests API request right
so you are basically creating a chain of
API request which basically work in a
particular sequence because first we
need to send the post request then we
need to send the get request and then we
need to send the delete request right so
that will be basically the sequence
and for that in order to have these all
these test cases in a sequence what we
can also do is let's go ahead and rename
this uh all these test cases okay
so let's go here and I'm going to
call it 0 1 underscore post request
and then 0 to underscore get request
and 0 3 underscore delete request right
so that we know that okay this is the
sequence uh which we have to execute
okay
also I'm going to drag it uh so that it
is in the correct sequence
so whenever we put it into an execution
list okay and we execute that execution
list it should be executed in this
particular order okay
so now uh first let's see how we can
execute it one by one and then maybe
we'll put it in execution list and we'll
execute it okay
so for now let me run this uh in
scratchbook and this is going to create
a new uh pet in that particular API
okay
and you can see it is going to buffer
that particular value so this is the ID
which has been returned and it has been
stored in B underscore pet ID right
so we have that value now and if we go
to get request we should be getting that
and we'll be using it for the pet ID
okay so let me go ahead and run this
okay so the pet ad is okay and we also
have a
the get response
now what we could also do is we can
verify the response status code for the
get request and the delete request so
let's go ahead and add them okay so if I
go to get response here and I am going
to add this status code okay
so don't worry about the 404 not found
that may have been scanned before I
executed this once and it failed okay
but we can change that so that's not a
problem
um and again I need to add this status
code into the delete request okay
so the minimum verification which you
can do for each uh API request is the
status code and apart from this you can
also verify other things uh whatever is
being returned on your response right
so here I am going to select two zero
zero okay and it will be action mode
verify
similarly for uh the delete response
right I'm going to again
select 200 okay and again it is verify
okay
so let's go ahead and execute this once
more just to check if the status code is
still uh the same
okay so we have got the status code now
and then the delete path right so let's
go ahead and execute this
okay and also this verification was
successful
so uh now we have executed all our test
cases using the correct values okay
which is uh the pet ID which we have
created earlier and then we are getting
that pet ID uh or getting the pet by
that ID and then we are deleting that
okay
so you can do a lot more verifications
like once it is deleted again you can do
a get petwa ID and you should not
basically have that so it should be a
known failure right because that pet ID
don't exist so you might get a 404 you
can verify that that is something which
is a negative test case right so once
the pet is deleted it should not be
present on the API so you should get a
404 okay
so these are these kind of things uh you
can still do but uh this will be the
process right uh and the last step would
be to just create uh execution folder
here okay
so uh first let me create a execution
folder here uh called that API
and then what I'm going to do is I'm
going to drag these three test cases
into this execution folder so that it
creates an execution list
and I can just call it uh
API requests
or API messages
okay
and I should make sure that they are in
the correct order so I will just drag it
so that
first the post request is processed and
then the get and then the delete okay
and then I can go ahead and execute this
and then all the results should be
available as an execution list right so
I can view it directly here all my
requests which is basically a request
and a response and I'm also verifying
the status code here and we can as I
said we can do a lot of other
verifications as well right
so you can see uh in the log info you
can verify uh what was the value set
here okay
and the same value was used here
so all of these things can be done okay
and in this way you can basically uh
scan your API messages you can then
export it back to your commander you can
create your test cases the required
modules you can add the module
attributes as business parameters and
then you can use it for verification in
your test cases along uh with buffering
other response values which can be used
in other requests okay
so this is basically a flow of how you
can test your apis
um within Tosca using the API scan and
Tosca Commander
there are lots of other functionalities
which we'll talk about in our coming up
sessions on this particular topic which
is API testing
so do tune in into our channel to watch
all these new videos if you have not
subscribed please subscribe so that you
get notified about all our new videos if
you want to keep learning Tosca and all
of its different features and
functionalities
so hope this video was helpful
um and you learned something new today
uh we'll come up with some more videos
as I talked about on API testing and
other topics so keep watching